Davide Vernizzi

Curriculum Vitæ

Via Belfiore, 42 10125, Torino, Italy \$\mathref{s}\mathre{s}\mathre{s} 329 24 73 484

 $\bowtie davide.vernizzi@gmail.com$

I am currently working as a software engineer at Ennova SrI, which was awarded with the prize of Italian Startup of Year 2014.

I develop web applications, backends, and APIs for mobile applications, which are mainly used by telecommunication companies and energy providers, such as Telecom Italia, Vodafone, Enel, and Iren Energia.

While working at Ennova, I have been in charge of integrating clients' databases, I developed web services used by clients' IVR, and I coordinated the efforts of Ennova's developers in order to develop various mobile apps. Moreover, I personally developed some of the most critical server side building blocks in many projects, and I have helped to design Ennova's cloud computing architecture.

Before working on web and mobile applications, I obtained a Ph.D in security of computer systems. In this context, I have participated in the European research project Open_TC, aimed at creating an open-source framework for Trusted Computing. Following this, I worked on security of cloud computing, contributing to the research project TClouds, whose goal was to create a resilient and privacy-friendly cloud computing platform.

While holding my positions, both in university and in industry, I have always been involved into the training of students or new employees.

Education

15 April 2010 Ph.D. in Computer Science, Politecnico di Torino.

Thesis: On Trusted and Privacy-Friendly Network Communications.

Advisor: prof. Antonio Lioy.

5 May 2006 M.Sc. in Computer Engineering, Politecnico di Torino.

Thesis: Self-adaptive parallel algorithms for computer vision applications. This thesis was written in collaboration with the École Nationale Supérieure d'Informatique et des Mathématiques Appliquées de Grenoble (ENSIMAG).

Advisors: prof. Bartrolomeo Montrucchio (POLITO), prof. Jean-Louis Roch (ENSIMAG).

11 July 2005 **Diplôme d'Ingénieur (equivalent to M.Sc. in Computer Engineering)**, École Nationale Supérieure d'Informatique et des Mathématiques Appliquées de Grenoble (ENSIMAG).

Thesis: Self-adaptive parallel algorithms for computer vision applications.

Advisor: prof. Jean-Louis Roch (ENSIMAG).

12 Sept. 2003 B.Sc. in Computer Engineering, Politecnico di Torino.

Work experience

since 2011 Developer, Ennova s.r.l, http://www.ennova.it/.

Development of web and mobile applications for customer care. Integration and development of enterprise services on behalf of telephone companies and energy providers.

2010 – 2011 Postdoctoral researcher, Politecnico di Torino, Dip. di Automatica e Informatica. Following the Ph.D I continued my research activity at Politecnico di Torino, focusing on Cloud Computing.

2006 – 2010 Research activity, Politecnico di Torino, Dip. di Automatica e Informatica.

Research activity at Politecnico di Torino on security of computer systems and network. The research activities were mainly focused to *Trusted Computing* and its application to network of computers, with a particular attention to privacy.

2009–2010 Consultant, SmartRM S.r.l., http://www.smartrm.com, Torino.

Consulting activity for SmartRM, a company specialized in developing encryption software that allows users to easily protect and share digital content. I helped SmartRM to integrate *Trusted Computing* principles to content protection.

2005 Internship, *ID-IMAG*, *http://bit.ly/id-imag*, Grenoble, Francia. Study and development of parallel algorithms used for computer vision.

2003, 2004 Internship, *Dynamic Fun S.r.l.*, http://www.dynamicfun.com/, Torino. Study and development of algorithms for face detection

Research projects

2010-2011 TClouds (Trustworthy Clouds), www.tclouds-project.eu.

Sviluppo di una piattaforma di Cloud Computing resiliente e privacy-enabled.

Principali partner: IBM, Philips, Ospedale San Raffaele (MI).

2010-2011 STORK (Secure Identity Across Borders Linked), www.eid-stork.eu.

Sviluppo di un sistema europeo interoperabile per l'autenticazione tramite elD.

Principali partner: 14 paesi membri dell'UE.

2007-2009 Open_TC (Open Trusted Computing), www.opentc.net.

Sviluppo di un framework per Trusted Computing, basato su software open source.

Principali partner: IBM, HP, Infineon, AMD.

Skills

OS Linux, Mac OS X, Windows Altro MySQL, UML, LATEX, Office

Programming C, Java, Python Web PHP, Javascript, HTML, CSS

Programming Trusted Platform Agent, http://security.polito.it/tc/tpa.

library C library (Linux, Windows) for application exploiting Trusted Computing and TPM.

Programming DAA Toolkit, http://security.polito.it/tc/daa.

library Patch for OpenSSL for anonymous authentication using TLS and DAA.

Web **sli-m.com**: **The slide machine**, http://sli-m.com.

Web service for making presentation basing on mind maps and LATEX/Beamer.

Languages and other information

Languages Fluent in English and French.

Teaching Teaching at Politecnico di Torino as teacher assistant and teaching to private com-

panies as teacher.